A Guide to The Papers of Fredson Thayer Bowers, [1595-1902], 1922-1992
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Group II: Writings
  - Editions (Copy Texts, Manuscript Material, Proofs,Background) (Box 7)
    - Essay Drafts (Publication Undetermined) (Box 85)
      - "Henry Vaughan's Symbols" 1957 (Box 85)
      - "Some Remarks on Bibliographical Evidence" 1958 (Box 85)
      - "Shakespeare's Text" 1959 (Box 85)
      - "The Problem of an Established Text and Definitive Edition" 1961 (Box 85)
      - "Editing of Literary Texts" 1963 (Box 85)
      - [Untitled], "In textual criticism what the author wrote constitutes authority..." 1970 (Box 85)
      - [Untitled], Fredson Thayer Bowers's specimen entry for Philobiblon 1970 (Box 85)
      - "Printer's Copy of Shakespeare's Folio, with Speculation about Ralph Crane" ca. 1972 (Box 85)
      - "Remarks Honoring Edgar Shannon" 1988 (Box 85)
      - "Notes on the Editing of Texts" 1989 (Box 85)
      - "Editing for Authentic Texts" n.d. (Box 85)
      - "Contaminated Text in Hamlet" n.d. (Box 85)
      - "Dramatic Structure and Criticism; Studied in Hamlet" n.d. (Box 85)
    - Textual Studies of Shakespeare (Manuscripts, Texts, Proofs,Background) (Box 86)
      - All's Well That Ends Well (Box 86)
      - Copy texts n.d., (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - Manuscript material 1973, n.d., (1-5 of 5 folders) (Box 86)
      - Box 87, (2-5 of 5 folders)
      - Proofs, n.d. (Box 87)
      - As You Like It (Box 88)
      - Copy texts, manuscript material and proofs n.d. (Box 88)
      - Comedy of Errors (Box 88)
      - Copy texts, manuscript material and proofs n.d. (Box 88)
      - Julius Caesar (Box 88)
      - Copy texts 1691, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 88)
      - Manuscript material 1970-89, n.d., (1-4 of 6 folders) (Box 89)
      - Box 90, (5-6 of 6 folders)
      - Proofs n.d. (Box 90)
      - Related correspondence 1971-85 (Box 90)
      - King Henry IV, Part I (Box 90)
      - Copy texts 1598-1639, n.d., (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 90)
      - Box 91, (3 of 3 folders)
      - Manuscripts and proofs 1968, n.d. (Box 91)
      - King Henry IV, Part II (Box 91)
      - Copy texts and proofs 1600, n.d. (Box 91)
      - King Henry V (Box 91)
      - Copy texts and related correspondence 1981, n.d. (Box 91)
      - King Lear (Box 91)
      - Copy texts n.d. (Box 91)
      - Manuscript material 1984, n.d. (Box 91)
      - King Richard II (Box 92)
      - Copy texts n.d. (Box 92)
      - Manuscript material 1972-73, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 92)
      - King Richard III (Box 92)
      - Manuscript material 1959, n.d. (Box 92)
      - Love's Labor's Lost (Box 92)
      - Copy texts and manuscript material n.d. (Box 92)
      - Measure for Measure (Box 93)
      - Copy texts 1951, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 93)
      - Manuscript material n.d., (1 of 3 folders) (Box 93)
      - Box 94, (4 of 4 folders)
      - Proofs n.d. (Box 94)
      - The Merchant of Venice (Box 94)
      - Copy texts and manuscript material n.d. (Box 94)
      - The Merry Wives of Windsor (Box 94)
      - Copy texts n.d. (Box 94)
      - A Midsummer Night's Dream (Box 94)
      - Copy texts, manuscript material and proofs n.d. (Box 94)
      - Othello (Box 94)
      - Copy texts n.d. (Box 94)
      - Manuscript material 1959 (Box 94)
      - Romeo and Juliet (Box 95)
      - Copy texts and manuscript material 1609, n.d. (Box 95)
      - The Taming of the Shrew (Box 95)
      - Copy texts 1972, n.d. (Box 95)
      - The Tempest (Box 95)
      - Copy texts 1972, n.d. (Box 95)
      - Titus Andonicus (Box 95)
      - Copy texts manuscript material 1611, n.d. (Box 95)
      - Tragedy of Coriolanus (Box 95)
      - Copy texts and proofs n.d. (Box 95)
      - Troilus and Cressida (Box 96)
      - Copy texts 1609-23, n.d., (1-4 of 6 folders) (Box 96)
      - Box 97, (5-6 of 6 folders)
      - Manuscript material n.d. (Box 97)
      - Twelfth Night (Box 97)
      - Manuscript material and related correspondence 1972, n.d. (Box 97)
      - Two Gentlemen of Verona (Box 97)
      - Copy texts n.d. (Box 97)
      - Manuscript material and proofs 1972, n.d. (Box 97)
    - Non-academic Writings (Print Material and Manuscripts) (Box 97)
      - Published articles (EC's):
        - as an Undergraduate 1923-25 (Box 97)
        - on Dogs 1934-76 (Box 97)
        - on Stamps 1956-58 (Box 97)
      - Unpublished:, (AMs and Ts) (Box 97)
        - "The Ideal Record Collector" 1961 (Box 97)
        - Fredson Thayer Bowers's music reviews of classical records 1939-67, (checklist) (Box 97)
- Group III: Academic and Personal
  - Articles and off-prints: on bibliography 1949-90, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 98)
  - on Bowers' writings 1967-88, n.d. (Box 99)
  - on Shakespeare 1940-89, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 99)
  - Honors: (Box 100)
  - Clark University, Doctor of Letters Degree 1970, (EC) (Box 100)
  - University of Virginia, Thomas Jefferson Award 1971, (EC) (Box 100)
  - University of Chicago, Doctor of Humane Letters Degree 1973, (with photo) (Box 100)
  - University of Virginia, career celebration keepsake 1974 (Box 100)
  - Eightieth-birthday conference tributes 1985, (Tss) (Box 100)
  - Julian P.Boyd Award, Association for Documentary Editing 1986 (Box 100)
  - Memorabilia: (Box 100)
  - Course thesis (Ts), "The Authorship of a Hundreth Sundrie Flowres" 1928 (Box 100)
  - Memorial Tributes: (Box 100)
  - Bibliographical Society of Australia and New Zealand 1991 (Box 100)
  - Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook 1991 (Box 100)
  - Documentary Editing, "In Memorium" by Jo-Ann Boydston, September, 1991 (Box 100)
  - "Reminiscences and Personal Recollections" by Fredson T.Bowers, Jr. 1991 (Box 100)
  - Date and address books, miscellaneous cards and ID's 1964-90, n.d. (Box 101)
  - Passports 1939-75 (Box 101)
  - Wine list, Villa Serbelloni 1969 (Box 101)
  - Yearbooks, The Irish Wolfhound Club of America 1927-65 (Box 101)
  - Miscellany: (Box 102)
  - Cancelled personal checks 1976 (Box 102)
  - Loose and unidentified manuscript material 1976, 1989, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 102)
  - Miscellaneous printed material 1968-88, n.d. (Box 103)
  - Photographs and prints 1971, n.d. (Box 103)
  - Professional association material 1967-82, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 103)
  - Publication contracts 1963-84, n.d. (Box 103)
  - Newsclippings: 1954-88 n.d. (Box 103)
  - Writings by other authors: (Box 103)
    - "Life Cycle of the Snowman," by Rudy Shackleford 1969-74 (Box 103)
    - "Poems for Fred and Nancy," by Elder Olson 1957, n.d. (Box 103)
    - "The Rationale of Copy-Text," by W.W. Greg (with correspondence) 1948-50, n.d. (Box 103)
    - "Infamous Woman: The Life of George Sand," by Joseph Barry 1976, (bound proof) (Box 104)
    - "Now and Another Time," by Shelby Hearon 1976, (bound proof) (Box 104)
    - "The Spectator Bird," by Wallace Stegner 1976, (bound proof) (Box 104)
    - "A Vein of Riches," by John Knowles 1978, (bound proof) (Box 104)
    - "The Woman Said Yes," by Jessamyn West 1976, (bound proof) (Box 104)
    - "Old Powder Man," by Joan Williams 1966, (page proof): (Box 104)
    - Autograph notes of James Southall Wilson on Shakespeare 1938-ca. 1954, n.d. (Box 104)
  - Teaching file: (Box 105)
    - Reference card index on general bibliography n.d. (Box 105)
    - (on variants in Shakespeare) n.d. (Box 106)
    - Shakespeare quiz Q & A's 1939-54, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - Student analyses of Shakespeare 1963-73, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 107)
    - Student dissertations 1973-79, (1 of 3 folders) (Box 107)
    - (2-3 of 3 folders) (Box 108)
    - Textbooks with Fredson Thayer Bowers' notes and marginalia 1933-41, Oversize (Box 108)
    - Copy Texts: Works of Christopher Marlowe, Vol. II 1598, 1622, (2 folders) (Box 108)
    - Works of Stephen Crane, Vol. III 1894-99, (5 folders) (Box 108)
    - Proof: Hamlet as Minister and Scourge 1989, (2 folders) (Box 108)
    - Poster: Fredson Thayer Bowers' lecture, Ohio State University 1968 (Box 108)